<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 on Ashton Shaffer</title>
    <link>/publication_types/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 on Ashton Shaffer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Ashton A. Shaffer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/publication_types/2/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Landscape of Living Kidney Donor Follow-up in the United States</title>
      <link>/publication/3-landscape-ldf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/3-landscape-ldf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Implementation of a Community Health Worker HIV Treatment and Prevention Intervention in an HIV Hot Spot Fishing Community in Rakai, Uganda</title>
      <link>/publication/2-mlake_training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2-mlake_training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovative approaches are needed to increase engagement in HIV treatment and prevention services, particularly in HIV hot spots. Here, we detail our design, training approach, and early implementation experiences of a community-based HIV intervention called &amp;ldquo;health scouts.&amp;rdquo; The intervention, utilizing a novel, theory-based approach, trained 10 community residents in an HIV hot spot fishing community to use motivational interviewing strategies and a mobile phone-based counseling application. During the first 3 months, 771 residents (median 82/health scout, range 27-160) were counseled. A directly observed Motivational Interviewing Treatment Integrity scale-based evaluation found adequate performance (median score &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;25&lt;/sub&gt;, range 11-23). The health scout intervention was feasible to implement in a high HIV-prevalence fishing community, and its impact on HIV care outcomes will be evaluated in an ongoing cluster randomized trial. If found to be effective, it may be an important strategy for responding to HIV in high-burden settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geophagy is associated with growth faltering in children in rural Bangladesh</title>
      <link>/publication/1-geophagia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/1-geophagia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine the relationship between geophagy (mouthing of dirt, sand, clay, or mud) and growth faltering in young children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We examined linear growth as height and weight standardized by age and sex, and weight standardized by height, in a cohort of children aged 6-36 months in rural Mirzapur, Bangladesh. We determined geophagy behavior at baseline through caregiver report. Anthropometric measurements were assessed at baseline and at a 1-year follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found that among children not stunted at baseline, those with caregiver-reported geophagy at baseline grew less over 1 year compared with their peers, with a difference in the change of standardized height for age and sex of -0.31 (95% CI, -0.61 to -0.01).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These findings show that caregiver-reported geophagy was associated with growth faltering in a pediatric population in rural Bangladesh. Future studies are needed to learn more about this exposure pathway and its relevance to child growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
